Welcome back to AP US History in under 3
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. So, I'm sure you are wondering
how the colonies are governing
themselves after this revolution. Well,
first, states throughout the Americas
around the end of the revolution started
implementing their own state
constitutions, which typically placed
power in a legislative branch and kept
that only people who owned property
could vote. However, these constitutions
showed America was not unified and
rather a bunch of separate states.
Something called the Articles of
Confederation were implemented at the
Second Continental Congress. However,
states didn't really recognize it. In
1781, by the end of the revolution, over
a ratification process of 4 years, the
Articles of Confederation finally came
into power. The Articles created a
central government for handling common
concerns of the states, like diplomacy,
defense, and managing western
territories. However, it was internally
weak to avoid the kind of centralized
authority that the colonies had rebelled
against. The federal government created
by the Articles could not enforce laws
directly on the states or citizens. It
had no power to tax and was largely
dependent on state cooperation. Despite
its weaknesses, the Articles did achieve
successes, such as the Northwest
Ordinance of 1787, which set up a
framework for westward expansion. It
established guidelines for admitting new
states, promoted public education,
protected private property, and banned
slavery in the Northwest Territory. But,
anyone could see that there was a
glaring issue with these Articles, and
this would lead to our next topic on the
Constitutional Convention. On the screen
now are AP style questions for this
topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
See you in the next one.